# Lewis Hill

# GAMEPLAY PROGRAMMER

lewishill.dev@gmail.com

Melbourne, Australia

<u>LinkedIn</u>

https://lewis-hill.github.io/

### Skills

C++/C#
Unreal Engine 5/Unity
Visual Studio
Perforce/Github
Jira

## Education

BA Hons -

Game Design And Art University of Southampton 2017-2020

#### **Hobbies**

Playing Games Bouldering Game Jams

# Strengths

Proactive
Quick to Learn
Communicative
Professional
Team Player

## **ABOUT ME**

My name is Lewis Hill, a Gameplay Programmer from the UK, currently based in Melbourne, Australia. I have worked professionally in Unreal Engine 5 to provide clients with intuitive Gameplay systems and tools that have the needs of Designers and other Programmers in mind, and are used to help create AAA experiences. I always seek a challenge and my passion for the field means I am constantly learning and improving my skills. Check out my portfolio website for examples of my newest projects.

# Experience



Gameplay Programmer – AAA Title in Unreal Engine 5 Climax Studios, Portsmouth UK February 2023 – September 2024

I am responsible for creating and taking ownership of key systems, such as an expanded Trigger Volumes and Overlap Management system and the base system for Moving Objects such as Platforms. I also responsible for creating and maintaining the base classes for interactable objects such as Containers and Pickups.

- Working closely with Designers to systemise various puzzle objects, ensuring they are easy to set up by providing editor tools and visualization, as well as maintaining Setup Documentation
- Collaborating with other Programmers through Code Reviews, Technical Design Documents and RFCs
- Communicating professionally with the client by offering relevant solutions to code implementations in meetings, as well as offering quick turnaround during key milestones

QA Tester – Returnal PC, Sackboy: A Big Adventure PC Climax Studios, Portsmouth UK August 2021 – February 2023

Assisted with porting AAA Playstation games to PC during later stage of development.

- Writing high quality and informative bugs
- Running and testing multiplayer features and test plans
- Multi-disciplinary communication